Previously on Transformers Prime:
在上一集里
Freak storms unlike any the region has seen,
可怕的风暴让当地人目瞪口呆
tsunamis threaten the Canadian coast,
海啸使加拿大沿岸岌岌可危
while lightning storms pummel the Gobi Desert.
雷暴也在戈壁滩上肆虐横行
I fear that the Earth's very core is not comprised of magma
恐怕 地核并不是由岩浆组成的
but of Dark Energon.
而是黑暗能量
By the allspark...
看在火种源的份上…
Cybertronian heartbeat?
塞博特恩人的心跳？
You mean something's living down there,
你的意思是 地底下有个活物
inside our planet?
就在地球里边？
Unicron, an ancient evil,
是“宇宙大帝” 远古的恶魔
whose fossilized blood comprises the matter which we call Dark Energon...
他的血液在石化之后 形成了我们所说的那种黑暗能量…
Pride for fool.
痴人说梦！
I have no need of your lowly assistance.
我无需一个下人插手此事
I'm detecting a swell of Unicron's spark activity.
擎天柱 我发现宇宙大帝火种的活性急剧增强
Now know me as Unicron, your destroyer!
现在 称我为宇宙大帝――你的毁灭者！
Optimus, have you uncovered any further sign of Unicron's emergence?
擎天柱 你发现宇宙大帝苏醒的其他迹象了吗？
Unicron is power incarnate,
宇宙大帝是力量的化身
and you, the last of the Primes,
而你 最后一个领袖
shall perish.
将步向死亡！
I take that as a yes.
看来回答是肯定的
We are on our way.
我们这就出发！
Negative.
不行
Unicron cannot be defeated by sheer force.
单靠蛮力是无法打倒宇宙大帝的
He wants me, Ratchet.
他要的是我 救护车
This fight must be mine alone.
这场战斗必须由我独自面对
Did Ratchet not relay my command?
难道救护车没有传达我的命令吗？
Return to base.
返回基地
Reinforcements will not prevent your destruction,
援兵也挽回不了你即将毁灭的下场
disciple of Primus.
原始天尊的门徒
Optimus, you are Unicron's target,
擎天柱 宇宙大帝的目标是你
maybe you should consider returning to the base.
也许你才应该返回基地
These manifestations of Unicron can locate me anywhere on Earth,
在宇宙大帝的化身面前 地球上没有任何藏身之处
even our base's shielding will only cloak my position for so long.
即使是基地的屏障 也只能在短时间内隐藏我的位置
I will not put others at risk.
我不能让其他人身处险境
Then fall back and let us take the lead,
那就撤退 我们来开路
just this once.
就这一次
Please listen to reason.
请理智一点吧
If you don't survive, Optimus,
万一你牺牲了 擎天柱
I fear neither will this planet.
恐怕这星球也活不成了
Very well.
那好吧
Let's move.
我们走！
No, not Unicron himself,
不 这不是宇宙大帝的真身
but another of his manifestations.
只是他的另一个化身而已
If we can't beat Unicron,
既然我们打不过宇宙大帝
and we can't out run him.
而且跑也跑不过他
What exactly are we supposed to do?
我们到底该怎么办？
All we can do...
我们所能做的…
neutralize his vassals as they appear,
只有尽快消灭这些傀儡
until we find a way to destroy him without destroying the very Earth upon which we walk.
直到找出办法 既能消灭他 又不必毁掉我们脚下的这颗星球
Fool.
愚蠢
I am this world's past, and its future,
我就是这个世界的过去 也是它的将来
and as of this moment...
鉴于目前的状况…
No!
不！
All Primes are simply past.
所有的领袖都将成为历史
Wasn't me.
不是我
Me neither.
也不是我
Ratchet?
救护车？
What is it? What happened?
怎么了？是谁干的？
I happened.
是我干的
Megatron!
威震天！
King Kong's there, too?
金刚虎王也来了？
He has aligned himself with Unicron.
他已经投靠了宇宙大帝
Don't be so sure.
别这么肯定
Megatron just saved Optimus' tailpipe.
威震天刚刚救了擎天柱的命
It is rather ironic considering our last encounter.
真是出乎意料 你我上次还刀兵相见
If my memory serves, you were desperately attempting to extinguish my spark.
如果没记错 你当时无论如何都要熄灭我的火种
That option remains very much in play.
那是我一贯的想法
I would expect nothing less.
我也不指望你心慈手软
However, I have a proposal.
不过 我有个提议
Join me in defeating our shared enemy,
和我联手 打败我们共同的敌人
Unicron, the Chaos Bringer.
宇宙大帝 混沌制造者
Ha! Absurd.
哈！荒唐！
Unicron is evil incarnate.
宇宙大帝是邪恶的化身
If Megatron was to take any side,
如果威震天要选择阵营的话
why would it be ours?
干嘛要选我们这边？
Because Megatron's pride would never allow anyone other than himself to rule this planet.
因为威震天的尊严使他不能容忍 自己以外的任何人统治这个星球
You know me all too well, Optimus.
你真是太了解我了 擎天柱
You lead an army of Cons,
你手下有一支虎头大军
why come to us?
还来找我们干嘛？
Because this particular endeavor requires something beyond the realm of my command--
因为这次特殊行动 需要一种我驾驭不了的力量――
-- the power of a Prime.
领袖的力量
Huh, then I guess we don't need you.
哼 那看来我们用不着你了
On the contrary,
恰恰相反
Optimus maybe the only one who can defeat Unicron,
擎天柱也许是唯一能击败宇宙大帝的人
but I remain the only one who can guide you to him.
但能带你们找到他的人 非我莫属
Unicron's life blood runs through me,
宇宙大帝的血液在我的体内流淌
only I can hear his thoughts,
只有我能听到他的思想
anticipate his movements.
可以抢先一步采取行动
Optimus, our past alliances--
擎天柱 我们过去的阵营
-- Autobot, Decepticon, no longer matter,
什么汽车人 霸天虎 都去他的吧
not while Unicron lives.
眼下 宇宙大帝复活了
The past always matters!
过去的事绝不能说算就算！
A truce between Autobot and Decepticon.
汽车人与霸天虎之间的停战协议
How long do you expect us to believe that will last?
你觉得 我们对它的信任度有多久？
Only as long is this mutually beneficial.
不过是维护共同的利益而已
And when our proposed to shared mission is complete?
那么 等到这个共同目标达成之后呢？
I will conquer this Earth,
我会征服这个星球…
my way.
用我的方式
Brutal honesty from a Decepticon?
霸天虎也会掏心窝子？
Aligning with the lesser of two evils is still siding with evil.
和小喽罗结盟 同样等于投靠大魔王！
Do you think you've witnessed the full power of Unicron?
你们以为自己见识过宇宙大帝的全力吗？
Those foot soldiers were nothing more than a taste.
那几个步兵连塞牙缝都不够
Unicron has yet to fully awaken.
宇宙大帝还没有完全苏醒
With each passing moment, the bringer of chaos evolves,
时间每过一分钟 混沌使者都会愈加强大
mutating Earth from the inside out.
把地球搅得天翻地覆
What we have witnessed until now is but a prelude
我们目前所见的 不过是个序幕
of the utter devastation his rising will wreak upon your world.
他的觉醒将给你们的世界带来无尽的浩劫
Like your quest for power destroyed Cybertron?
就像你为了追求权力 毁掉塞博特恩那样？
Make no mistake.
别搞错了
This time there will be a planet left for me to rule.
这一次 肯定会有一颗星球留给我统治
Even if we agree,
即使我们同意
Unicron is all the way down at the center of the Earth.
可宇宙大帝身处在地球的中心
How are we supposed to get there? Drive?
我们要怎么下去？开车吗？
There is only one way.
只有一条路
Absolutely not!
绝对不行！
Ground bridging into space or onto moving train is difficult enough,
传送到太空 或是行进中的列车上 已经够困难了！
but plotting a blind jump inside of a sentient being?
这次居然要漫无目的地传送到 一个智慧生命体内部？
Besides, direct expose to that much Dark Energon will debilitate you.
更何况 直接暴露在那么多的黑暗能量下 会让你们浑身无力
You haven't built up immunity like Megatron has.
你们可没有威震天那种免疫力
Yet another strong argument for solidarity,
这正是我们联手的另一个好处：
my guidance.
我可以当向导
You can provide Unicron's exact coordinates?
你能提供宇宙大帝精确的坐标吗？
If you transport us to this planet's core,
如果你能把我们传送到星球的核心
I can lead you directly to Unicron's spark,
我就能直接带你们找到宇宙大帝的火种
the very heart of his darkness.
那可是黑暗力量的心脏！
Optimus, even if we survive the jump,
擎天柱 即使我们在传送后能活下来
how are we supposed to stop Unicron?
又该怎么阻止宇宙大帝呢？
With the Matrix of Leadership.
用领导模块
What is that?
那是什么？
A vessel of pure energy,
一个装有纯粹能量的容器
the collective wisdom of the Primes.
历届领袖智慧的结晶
Do we have time for a scavenger hunt?
我们还有寻宝的时间吗？
I mean where is Optimus supposed to find this Matrix?
我是说 擎天柱该去哪儿找这个“模块”呢？
Optimus does not need to find it.
擎天柱不需要寻找
He carries it within him.
他一直把它带在身上
It was the combined power of the Primes that defeated Unicron so long ago,
很久以前 领袖们依靠这种融合的力量 才战胜了宇宙大帝
the very reason he now seeks to destroy you.
这也是他现在想要摧毁你的原因
It would follow that unleashing the power of the Matrix directly into Unicron's spark
照这么说 将领导模块的力量 直接灌进宇宙大帝的火种
would return him to stasis.
就可以让他重新长眠
Hold on.
等等
If everything goes right,
如果一切都顺利进行的话
Unicron's gonna stay down there?
宇宙大帝就会一直待在地下喽？
Yeah, can we sent them out somehow?
是啊 能不能…想办法把他除掉？
He is not in the Earth's core, Jack.
他不是住在地核里 杰克
He is the Earth's core.
他就是地核
Rafael is correct.
拉斐尔说的对
Tempering with your core could affect the magnetic poles,
扰动地核可能会影响磁极
trigger the very cataclysmic events we are attempting to remedy.
反而引发一些我们本该避免的特大灾难
Tragically, Unicron is your planet's very seed,
可惜的是 宇宙大帝正是你们星球的起源
always has been and always must be.
从古至今 直到遥远的将来
We got another one.
又来了一个
Ratchet, set the GroundBridge.
救护车 打开环陆桥
Wait, we're opening up a direct path into our base with Megatron standing right there?
等等 我们就这么打开一条直通基地的大道 让威震天看热闹？
And seriously,
说真的
he's gonna risk his own spark to save us?
他真能拼了他的火种 给我们擦屁股吗？
Haha... hardly my nature.
哈哈哈 的确不是我的本性！
Consider my offer.
考虑一下我的提议
I shall keep it busy.
我来拖住它
No word yet from Lord Megatron?
还没有威震天陛下的消息吗?
It appears our leader has abandoned us while this world erupts in chaos.
看来统帅弃我们而去了 把我们扔在这个混乱的世界
I believe we must consider the possibility of the future without Megatron.
我认为 我们必须做出长远的打算 无需考虑威震天了
I know the desperate times call for desperate measures,
我知道 紧要关头需要采取非常措施
but bringing Megatron here?
可你真要放威震天进来吗？
How can you even think about letting that monster near these children after what he did to Raf?
怎么能让那怪物靠近孩子们 你忘了他差点害死拉夫吗？
He will be closely monitored,
我们会严密监视他
and only allowed to linger long enough to send us on our journey,
并且仅仅让他逗留到带我们上路为止
not one moment more.
一刻也不多留
What's gonna stop the Con from calling in air strike could be he knows where you live?
那家伙难道不会呼叫空袭吗？反正他知道你的位置
By ground bridging Megatron here,
我们用环陆桥带威震天进来
he will be unable to get a fix on our coordinates.
他无法确认我们的具体坐标
Optimus, what's gonna happen to you when all your... Matrix energy's released?
擎天柱 到时你会怎么样？我是说 模块能量释放之后
The power within the Matrix has not previously been utilized in this particular manner.
模块中的力量 从未以这种方式被使用过
But you have an idea, don't you?
但你总该知道个大概 对吧？
Autobots, if humankind is to be saved,
汽车人 为了拯救人类
I have no choice but to proceed,
我没有选择 只能前进
but you do.
但你们可以选
Well, I don't know about humankind,
其实 我不了解人类
but I'm willing to do it,
但我愿意这么做
for Miko.
就为神子
For Jack.
为杰克
Megatron, we are sending transport.
威震天 我们这就接你过来
You can always be relied upon to listen to reason, Optimus.
你始终是个通情达理的人 擎天柱
No fair! I've never seen him!
不公平！我还没见过他呢！
Why do we have to hide?
我们干嘛要藏起来？
Because I said so.
因为我说了算
So this is where the magic happens.
看来 这就是大变活人的地方
Quaint.
古色古香
- Raf! - Rafael, no!
- 拉夫！
You!
你！
Ah, you're looking much better than the last time we met, little one.
啊 你看起来比上次见面时精神多了 小东西
Humans, resiliant.
人类啊 真顽强
Come on Raf.
来吧 拉夫
He isn't worth it.
他不值得你拼命
And you, I never forget a face even that of a human.
还有你 我对面孔过目不忘 人类的也算上
You double-cross anyone,
你要是敢骗人
mine is the face you'll never forget, never!
我让你永远忘不了我这张脸 给我记住！
Ratchet, obtain the destination coordinates from our guest.
救护车 从我们的客人那里接收目的地坐标
Jack,
杰克
will you keep something for me?
你能帮我保管一样东西吗？
Sure.
当然
What is it?
这是什么？
It is the key to the GroundBridge power supply.
这是…环陆桥电源的钥匙
Ok, but shouldn't Ratchet have this?
好吧 可这不该让救护车保管吗？
Perhaps,
或许吧
but I've been impressed by how much you have matured since we first met.
让我感到欣慰的是 你比我们最初见面时要更加成熟
As such,
因此
I feel you've earned the responsibility of safeguarding this important device,
我觉得 你完全可以担当保管这个重要器物的责任
until I return.
直到我回来为止
I won't let you down.
我不会让你失望的
Locked and ready.
目标锁定
You first.
你先
As you wish.
如你所愿
So how long before Unicron knows we're here?
那个…宇宙大帝何时才会发现我们？
Make no mistake.
别搞错了
He already does.
他已经知道了